[whimpering]
[metallic clinking]
[continues whimpering]
[man 1 grunts]
[boy crying]
[man 2 gasping, panting]
[man 3 grunts]
[boy crying]
[♪ tense music playing]
[whimpering]
Press forward!
Protect the villagers!
[soldier panting]
[grunts]
[soldiers screaming]
♪
[soldier gasps]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
EPISODE 34:
A DEMON-SLAYING REQUEST
30 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE RUFEN REGION,
LOCATED ON THE NORTHERN PLATEAU
♪
Show mercy.
Please, I have a son.
He is but a child.
[GENAU] Silence.
Your trite words move me not.
I've heard them more times
than I can count.
[GENAU] Mm...
[Genau sighs]
[footsteps]
Well, demon?
Where is this
supposed child of yours?
At least try peppering
some fact into your fiction,
would you?
♪
[GENAU] The demon-slaying
request came directly
from Mistress Serie.
I wasn't certain
what I would find.
But it seems my hometown
was the target
of the demonic rampage.
I bear no sentimental attachment
to this place,
but it does sadden me
to see it like this.
-[wood creaks]
-[man breathes shakily]
Genau. You?
[GENAU] Yes.
[MAN] Demons.
They destroyed the village.
I'm well aware.
It's been dealt with.
I took care
of the assailants myself.
[MAN]
What about the others?
They're all safe.
Every last one.
You'll be all right, too.
A newly qualified
first-class mage
is here with me.
I'm taking you to her now.
This particular mage has been
blessed with the ability
to use the Goddess' magic.
Unusual, isn't it?
She'll be able to heal
your wounds with great ease,
so you can reopen
that shop of yours in no time.
I wonder...
Have you finally learned
how to bake
a decent loaf of bread?
The only bread that has
crossed my plate recently
has been cold and hard.
Something warm
and fresh from the oven
would be a welcome change.
In truth, it needn't be
either of those things.
I'd take a heel
from your unsold leftovers
or a crumb
from an old failure.
[Genau sighs]
I'm not too picky.
♪
[METHODE] Mr. Genau...
[Methode sighs]
Bring the injured over here.
[GENAU] Injured?
You needn't spare
my feelings, Methode.
And tact is wasted on him.
He's dead.
He was well past
the point of saving
by the time I pried him
from the rubble.
The stench is dreadful.
His stomach wound
was already rotting
when I found him.
Someone so far gone
can't be saved.
Yet, even at death's door,
he clung to me with
all the strength he had.
[Genau grunts]
[GENAU] He was the son
of the village baker.
We played together as children
in these very streets.
When his father passed,
he took over the shop
and began baking in his stead.
No matter how much he tried,
his bread was never very good.
♪
And now I will never
taste it again.
Well, at least
with the others beside him,
he won't be lonely.
Why does it have to be
them lying here
instead of the two of us?
We launch ourselves into peril
of our own free will.
The people of this village
were given no such choice.
♪
[GENAU] If anyone has to die,
it should be
the first-class mages like us
who choose a life
of conflict and chaos.
[METHODE] Mr. Genau...
By the time the request
from the Chivalric Order of Norm
stationed here
reached the northern branch,
this village had already
been destroyed.
You are not responsible
for what happened.
I'll take another look
around the village.
At this point,
rest might be more prudent
than reconnaissance.
How so?
Must you ask?
[GENAU] Quiet.
One of my surveilling eyes
was blinded.
I'm sensing a lone warrior.
And one mage
trying to stay hidden.
Or is it two?
[METHODE] It's two.
[GENAU] They must be skilled
to have dodged detection.
Do you think they're enemies?
I don't. Looks to me
like they're...
♪
Frieren, what a surprise.
[Methode sighs]
Which must mean
the other signature I detected
belongs to the
first-class mage, Fern.
♪
And who's this?
Methode, of course.
And the proctor from
the first-class mage exam.
I believe it was Genau, yes?
I fear you've caught me
backfooted.
There was so much bloodlust
in that spell,
I'd assumed you a demon.
Was there? I apologize
for the confusion.
No harm meant.
I felt it, too.
You had me worried to death
for a moment there.
[FRIEREN] Fern, it's okay.
They're on our side.
Tell Stark to stand down.
[FERN] All right.
How curious.
I suppose, Miss Fern,
you also received
a demon-slaying request?
We were just
conveniently located.
Tell me, what happened?
[footsteps]
Are you praying for them?
You mind?
[GENAU] No, I don't think so.
My village was destroyed
by demons, too.
I see.
Hey...
The whole thing with demons
is that they eat people.
So why are the bodies
still intact?
It was the same at my village.
Who can say? I surely can't.
Demons will kill humans
even when they're
perfectly sated.
The logic eludes me.
That makes sense.
The two of you
would be force enough
for a few stray demons.
Seems we were
a step behind this time.
And all our hurrying
was ultimately for naught.
Not entirely, perhaps.
There's a loose end Mr. Genau
wants to tie.
[FRIEREN] Hm.
♪
[GENAU] These men were with
the Chivalric Order of Norm.
[STARK] What is that?
[FRIEREN]
We encountered them
in the Norm Company territory,
remember?
They're the trading company's
military force.
I'm surprised there were
so few of them.
[GENAU] A standard number
to see garrisoned
in a village of this size.
For as few as there were,
they were a greater caliber
of guard
than the village deserved.
[FERN] Uh...
[GENAU] The man in the middle
was their captain.
He was an exceptional soldier
who'd defended
the village for years.
[FRIEREN] How surprising.
The strength he bore
puts Stark's to outright shame.
Yeah, well, that's not exactly
a high bar to clear.
Have you determined
the cause of death?
I cast an autopsy spell.
Consistent with their wounds,
they died to a blade.
Death was instantaneous.
The demons in the village
were weak.
Weak enough that
soldiers of this skill
should have obliterated them.
There's no doubt
the true architect
of this massacre
is still at large.
Take heart. It would appear
your journey here
wasn't a waste after all.
[Fern and Stark sigh]
[FRIEREN] Indeed.
I'm glad there's some service
we can do these fallen.
This demon... let's find it
and show it how terrifying
humanity can be.
♪
Across once.
Twice. Hold.
Perhaps a jab?
I'm no sword fighter,
but those moves are unrealistic.
[METHODE] Nevertheless,
they align
with the knights' wounds.
It doesn't make sense.
Unless it fought
with two swords.
Aren't you clever?
♪
The first clue about our culprit
is that demons typically
only conceal their mana
for short bursts.
So we can assume this demon
is currently outside
mana detection range.
Meaning the immediate area
around this village is safe.
[FRIEREN] Genau shared with me
a few nearby locations
where demons are known
to establish bases.
We should focus
our search there.
Right.
[FRIEREN] Hm.
First, I suppose we should
get dinner out of the way.
Your skills are sharper
after a healthy meal.
[FERN] Hm.
You're feeding us
more "clunk" bread?
The logistics network can't be
rebuilt overnight, complainer.
Where's Genau?
Last I saw him,
he was still at the church.
I can drop by now
to deliver his share of bread.
Wait. While you're here,
we could use your analysis
of the enemy.
Understanding
its composition is vital.
[STARK] I don't mind being
the delivery boy.
Thank you, Stark.
Fill us in.
Are there any new discoveries?
I'm not prepared to make
a definitive statement
about the demon's
physical composition
at this point,
but I do have
a leading theory.
-[crunching]
-Right, then.
We should develop
our strategy immediately.
[FERN] Huh?
[Methode exclaiming]
On second thought,
the war room shall open
after dinner.
♪
[GENAU] What now?
Are they ready to move?
No, sir.
I just brought you your dinner.
[crunching]
[Genau grunts softly]
[GENAU] It's hard.
[Stark, muffled] I know.
[in normal voice]
So, what were you doing?
[GENAU] In the chaos, the demons
destroyed the church's barrier.
I was simply replacing it
with a stronger one.
The villagers' corpses
are inside, after all.
Really?
You sure you want to leave them
laying on the floor like that?
If you need a hand,
I'll help bury them.
I'm good at manual labor stuff.
Of course.
You're not from
the Northern Plateau,
so I shouldn't expect you
to understand.
[STARK] Hm?
Villages here generally
don't have graveyards
like you do in the south.
[GENAU] On rare occasion,
you'll find one tucked
into the corner
of a fortress city.
Other graves are reserved
for nobles
and protected by
strong barriers.
The southern border is dotted
with a series
of common graveyards.
The average man is buried there,
where there are fewer demons.
Transporting the corpses
is a massive ordeal.
The Chivalric Order of Norm
sends an escort.
Do you know why
the stakes are so high?
No.
If they don't practice
great caution,
the smell of decay
will attract bloodthirsty demons
by the score.
It is a truly hellish sight.
Not even the bones
are left behind.
For a long while now,
the Norm Company has campaigned
for the people of the Plateau
to cremate their dead.
It's the kind
of rational thinking
you would expect
from merchants.
And I agree with it.
♪
[GENAU]
But the clergy have voiced
their opposition
to the practice.
I also understand
how they feel...
from deep in my soul.
To suggest burning people
who have already suffered
gruesome deaths?
It's simply inhumane.
Alas, we'll eventually
have to accept it.
If we can't face facts,
no one will be able
to rest in their homeland.
♪
[crunching]
If you could only hear us
and not see us,
you would think we were
kicking rocks.
[METHODE]
It's a welcome surprise,
but sharing a meal
with you two
is certainly surprising.
I had a strong feeling
we would meet again,
but a village
destroyed by demons
wasn't the backdrop I imagined.
[FRIEREN]
This wasn't in our plan.
We set up camp on the other side
of the mountain.
I was anticipating
a perfectly average stay.
This request was
quite the shock.
♪
[Frieren snores]
Huh? We've got a new buddy.
It looks like he has a letter.
I'm very curious as to
what you and Genau are doing
this far up north.
I find it hard to believe
two other first-class mages
just happened to be
milling around
near the scene
of the crime.
That's fair. Though,
I can assure you
there has been
no milling around.
We're both here
on direct orders.
Mistress Serie asked us
to come north
to contain the demon population.
[FRIEREN] I didn't realize
first-class mages
had those kind of obligations.
I'm glad I didn't become one.
I don't doubt that much.
But I'm actually here
as her apprentice.
Is that so?
[METHODE] Yes.
It's very typical
for first-class mages
to become Mistress Serie's
apprentices
at one point or another.
Now that you say it,
I think I've heard it
mentioned before.
Be proud to know
I turned her down.
[FRIEREN]
You're a good girl, Fern.
So that's why
the two of you gave in
to Serie's
unreasonable demands.
She must be
running you ragged.
I promise it isn't so bad.
If anything,
I wish I could be
of greater use to her.
My darling mistress
is a devastatingly
adorable creature.
Is she really?
[METHODE] You should know,
Miss Frieren.
You're just as precious
as she is.
Why, thank you.
[Fern grunts]
Good Mr. Genau
on the other hand...
He's a great example
of how not to behave.
[GENAU] Methode,
do not end up like me.
[FRIEREN] Well, now that
our bread is out of the way,
we have much
strategizing to do.
[GENAU] So, how is the analysis
of the enemy coming along?
[STARK] Hm.
[GENAU]
Have you learned anything?
Yeah.
Methode is still putting
together the final details,
but we're getting closer.
And there's one thing
that we know for sure.
♪
[FRIEREN] Didn't you say
the enemy fought
with two swords?
[METHODE] I did.
[FERN AND FRIEREN] Huh?
But upon further investigation,
it seems we were wrong.
The wounds inflicted
and typical technique
don't align.
What do you mean?
While I'm not an expert,
dual wielding
is all about balance.
One blade is used for offense
and the other reserved
for defensive maneuvers.
The first blade is a longsword
to inflict fatal blows,
and the second blade
is typically
a lighter short sword
that's easier to move.
Therefore, we should be
seeing wounds inflicted
from two distinct weapons.
♪
Isn't it possible that the demon
we're looking for
is strong enough to wield
two longswords?
Good thought.
We had it, too.
But after trying
to recreate the same cuts
we found on the dead,
we were able to rule out
that possibility.
[FERN] Hmm.
To successfully
reproduce the damage,
our movements were
incredibly unrealistic.
I will warn you
that what comes next
is pure speculation.
Speculate freely.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
That was me.
[Stark grunts]
[Methode sighs]
[♪ intense music playing]
[Methode grunts softly]
The enemy...
It wields four blades.
[GENAU] Interesting.
Based on all the cuts
on the knights' bodies
and the surrounding buildings,
it was the best conclusion
we could come up with.
♪
Four blades, you say.
[crunches]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[FERN]
I'm severely outclassed.
[STARK] You don't have
that choice.
[REVOLTE] You seem to know
who I am.
[FRIEREN] It's likely
the beast's appearance...
[METHODE] One of them
was a demon general.
[GENAU]
"The Divine Revolte."